# Apramey Bhat

Summary

A master's student at Aalto University with a focus on security and cloud computing and four years of experience as a software engineer. I am looking for a new challenge in progressive, customer-focused, and industrial research-oriented firm where I can maximize my passion of technology and broaden my understanding of user-centered techniques.

Some of the keywords that are found in my LinkedIn recommendations from my past acquaintances are: soft spoken, humble, blends with team, ownership, dedication, commitment, quick learner, go an extra mile to close tasks, logical reasoning, go to person etc.

#### Education

Aug 2022 -

Aalto University, Espoo, Finland

Present

Master's Program in Security and Cloud Computing – SECCLO (Erasmus Mundus Joint Master's Degree)

2014 - 2018

SDM College of Engineering and Technology, Dharwad, India.

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science. (Grade: 9.03/10)

#### **Professional Experience**

Sep 2022 -

Teaching Assistant, Aalto University

Oct 2022 | School (Part time) | • Res

School of Science, Espoo, Finland

- Responsible for assisting students with the assignments for the course CS-C3130 Information Security
- Assignments: Access Control, SQL Injection, Password Cracking, Web Insecurity, Buffer Overrun, XSS

Dec 2020 -Aug 2022 (Full time)

#### Senior Software Engineer, First American Financial Corporation

Business Technology Solutions Team, Bengaluru, India

- Responsible for architecting and developing solutions for a data reconciliation project involving inhouse product integrations
- Application Security:
  - Developed a generic authentication/authorization layer with Azure Active Directory, OAuth 2.0 and JWT
  - Resolved multiple application vulnerabilities such as Cross-site scripting XSS, External XML Entities, and SQL Injection etc.
  - Completed Veracode Application Security Professional exam with 94.7% grade, which involved 35 courses [Transcript]
- Full Stack Development & Cloud Solutions:
  - Implemented a highly available and scalable Virtual Private Cloud environment involving AWS Step Functions, Lambda, AWS RDS, AWS SNS, API Gateway, Elastic Load Balancers abiding by pub/sub pattern and command pattern
  - Designed and developed a suite of 50+ REST APIs and services with serverless and microservices architecture
  - Developed a Rule Engine based on Rete Algorithm for on-the-go reconciliation of financial data between multiple systems
  - Redesigned existing APIs that bring execution data, reducing 67% of memory footprint
- Involved in architecture discussions and peer code reviews
- The data reconciliation project is anticipated to save around \$22M per year
- Tech Stack: .Net Core, AWS Cloud Services, Angular, TIBCO EMS, OAuth 2.0

July 2018 -Dec 2020 (Full time)

#### **Product Engineer, INSZoom** (A Mitratech Company)

Product Development Team, Bengaluru, India

- Application Security:
  - Spearheaded a team of 4 to rewrite the user role management module which involved changes in the authorization middleware
  - Integrated INSZoom with monitoring services like *Elmah* and *NewRelic*, to get the streamlined error and vulnerability reports
  - Identified and solved multiple **CWE** listed vulnerabilities found in the product
- Full Stack Development & Cloud Solutions:
  - Part of 20+ full stack revamp projects that involved reactive frontend framework and microservices architecture; Laid the groundwork for x10 traffic scale into the newly designed product
  - Introduced lossless data compression on servers, that reduced hosted file size by 73%, in turn increasing page load time
- The newly built INSZoom product increased the company revenue to \$25M and the product went global with immigration case management workflows supporting 100+ countries
- Promoted to **Core Tech Team** where I was involved in various proof-of-concept projects, design discussions, articulating technical whitepapers and code reviews
- Tech Stack: Net Core, Net WebAPI, SQL, Vue.js, Vuex, Webpack, RabbitMQ, Bootstrap, Elastic Search, AWS S3, Azure

Feb 2018 -May 2018 (Part time)

#### **Product Engineer - Intern, INSZoom** (A Mitratech Company)

Product Development Team, Bengaluru, India

- Worked on fixing vulnerabilities and bugs of various modules of the product, thereby increasing code quality and KPI of modules
- Tech Stack: ASP.Net MVC, SQL, .Net WebAPI, JavaScript, JQuery, Azure

#### Relevant Skills

Frameworks Database .Net Core, .Net Web API, Node.is, Flask, Vue.is, React, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, xUnit, Caffe

Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB

Tools & Lib.

Github, Git, Dapper, Moq, Axios, TIBCO EMS, RabbitMQ, Docker, OpenCV

Cloud

AWS Cloud Solutions (EC2, S3, SNS, SQS, Lambda, RDS, Step Functions, Cloudwatch), Google Cloud Platform

(ComputeEngine, Firebase, Tensorflow), Terraform Scripting

Languages

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Java, C

### Extracurricular Activities & Achievements

#### Volunteering

- Volunteer at **Slush**, as well as a participant and volunteer at **Junction** [2022]
- Teaching Assistant at Google Developer Days India [2017]
- Student Facilitator for Google Applied CS Skills with Android at SDMCET [Success Story] [2017-2018]
- Graphic Designer and Co-ordinator for different contests at Insignia for a stretch of 4 years at SDMCET [2014 -2018]
- Internshala Student Partner for SDMCET Dharwad [2017-2018]

## Trainings &

- Veracode certified Application Security Professional [Feb'21]
- **Certifications** Architecting on AWS, AWS Technical Essentials, AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials [Sep'21]

#### **Awards**

- Top Performer Q1 2022 First American Financial Corporation [2022]
- Zoom Star Top 3 engineers in INSZoom to get awarded by the CEO [2020]
- Zoom Miles Champion (thrice) Quarterly Award presented in INSZoom [2018-2020]
- The undergraduate final year thesis project was selected as **Top 3000 Startups in India** by IIM Calcutta, India [2018]

**Test Scores** • TOEFL iBT – **102/120** (R:22, L:29, S:23, W:28) [Issued on: May 17, 2021]

#### Spoken Languages

- English (Fluent)
- Kannada, Hindi, Tulu (Native)
- Finnish (Beginner)

#### References (Contact info available on request)

- Vinay Kalasannavar (Tech Lead, Mitratech)
- Anil Pujeri (Engineering Manager, SenseHawk)
- Dr. Shrihari Joshi (Professor, SDMCET)